Please have a seat.
앉아주세요.
Sir.
선생님.
Okay.
좋아요.
Sir,
선생님,
what can I do for you?
내가 당신을 위해 무엇을 할 수?
Please give this to Ms. Lin and tell her that I am here for her.
이것을 Ms. Lin에게 주고 내가 그녀를 위해 여기 있다고 전해주세요.
=Ripe Town= =Episode 9=
=익은 마을= =에피소드 9=
The beard is different.
수염이 다릅니다.
It can't be painted like how you do your eyebrows.
눈썹처럼 그릴 수는 없습니다 .
I actually don't know how to do my eyebrows well.
사실 저는 눈썹을 잘 그리는 방법을 모르겠어요 .
You really look like your father.
당신은 정말로 당신의 아버지를 닮았습니다.
I saw your brother on the street.
길에서 네 동생을 봤어.
He looks more like your mother.
그 사람은 네 엄마를 더 닮았어.
You are more like your father.
당신은 당신의 아버지와 더 비슷합니다.
I knew you had an affair with my father.
나는 당신이 우리 아버지와 바람을 피우고 있다는 것을 알고있었습니다.
My mother knew it too.
우리 엄마도 그걸 알고 계셨어요.
Do you resent me?
당신은 나를 원망합니까?
Maybe when I was a child.
아마도 내가 어렸을 때였을 것이다.
But now if you ask me,
하지만 지금 나에게 묻는다면,
I can't say what you did wrong.
나는 당신이 무엇을 잘못했는지 말할 수 없습니다.
I don't know many things about my father,
나는 아버지에 대해 아는 것이 많지 않다 .
but I think you should know.
하지만 내 생각엔 당신이 알아야 할 것 같아요.
I wanted to ask you a long time ago.
예전부터 묻고 싶었어요.
What do you want to ask?
무엇을 묻고 싶나요?
I will tell you what I know.
내가 아는 것을 말해 주겠다.
Did my father only come to see you every time he came here?
우리 아버지는 여기 올 때마다 너만 보러 오셨나요 ?
Yes.
예.
He only visited me every time.
그는 매번 나를 방문했습니다.
He had never looked for anyone else.
그는 결코 다른 사람을 찾지 않았습니다.
Don't men love juggling different women?
남자들은 다른 여자와 저글링하는 것을 좋아하지 않습니까?
Your father didn't.
네 아버지는 그렇지 않았어.
Are you here to ask me about your father?
아버지에 대해 물어보러 왔나요 ?
Not really.
설마.
But tell me about him first.
하지만 먼저 그에 대해 말해주세요.
My parents died during a plague.
부모님은 전염병으로 돌아가셨습니다.
I was sold to Cuihua Tower by my uncle when I was 11.
저는 11살 때 삼촌에 의해 취화탑에 팔렸습니다 .
I started learning painting and calligraphy,
그림 과 서예를 배우기 시작했는데 ,
playing music, and singing songs
음악을 연주하고, 노래를 부르며
till 14.
14까지.
My menstruation came late, giving me another year of an easy life.
월경이 늦어지면서 1년은 더 편안한 삶을 살 수 있게 되었습니다.
But when I was 15,
하지만 제가 15살이었을 때,
the day finally came.
드디어 그날이 왔다.
I had to entertain guests.
손님을 대접해야 했어요.
I found an opportunity
나는 기회를 찾았다
to escape.
탈출.
You ran from Cuihua Tower?
취화탑에서 도망쳤나요?
Where did you run?
어디로 달려갔나요?
I had nowhere to go.
나는 갈 곳이 없었다.
I didn't know the way.
나는 그 길을 몰랐다.
I didn't have any money.
나는 돈이 없었습니다.
But weren't you afraid of running into bad guys?
하지만 나쁜 놈들과 마주칠까봐 두렵지 않았나요 ?
Before thinking of that,
그런 생각을 하기 전에,
I encountered one.
나는 하나를 만났다.
Girl, stop. I'm not a bad guy.
아가씨, 그만해요. 나는 나쁜 사람이 아닙니다.
I told you to stop.
나는 그만하라고 말했다.
Let me take good care of you.
내가 당신을 잘 보살펴 드리겠습니다.
Let go!
가자!
Get lost.
길을 잃다.
Don't be afraid. I'm an official.
두려워하지 마십시오. 나는 공무원입니다.
Where do you live? I can take you home.
어디 살아요? 집에 데려다줄 수 있어요.
Stop following me.
따라 다니지 말아 줘.
I am a bailiff from the Yamen.
저는 야멘의 집행관입니다.
Tell me where your home is.
집이 어디인지 말해 보세요.
I will take you home.
내가 집에 데려다줄게.
Mind your own business.
니 일이나 신경써.
I didn't break the law.
나는 법을 어기지 않았습니다.
You're a young girl,
당신은 어린 소녀입니다.
walking alone in the middle of the night,
한밤중에 혼자 걷고 ,
and you can't tell where to go.
그리고 어디로 가야할지 말할 수 없습니다.
Honestly,
솔직히,
I can take you to the Yamen.
당신을 야멘으로 데려갈 수 있어요.
If you don't tell me,
나한테 말하지 않으면,
I will do that.
나는 그렇게 할 것이다.
I have nowhere to go.
나는 갈 곳이 없다.
What?
무엇?
How can you have nowhere to go?
어떻게 갈 곳이 없나요?
I ran away from a place.
나는 한 곳에서 도망쳤다.
What?
무엇?
From where?
어디서?
Are you
당신은
a maid from a wealthy family,
부유한 집안의 하녀,
or a girl from a brothel?
아니면 매음굴의 여자인가요?
Cuihua Tower.
추이화 타워.
If you want to go back there,
다시 그곳으로 돌아가고 싶다면,
I can take you back.
나는 당신을 다시 데려갈 수 있습니다.
Please don't take me back.
제발 나를 다시 데려가지 마세요.
If they know I escaped,
내가 탈출한 걸 그들이 알면,
they will kill me.
그들은 나를 죽일 것이다.
I can help you.
제가 도와드릴 수 있어요.
I will make up a story to cover for you.
나는 당신을 위해 이야기를 만들 것입니다.
When you were kidnapped by a villain,
악당에게 납치당했을 때,
I happened to see you.
우연히 당신을 만났습니다.
I drove away the villain and saved you.
악당을 몰아내고 당신을 구해줬어요.
I'm a bailiff, and they will believe me.
나는 집행관이고 그들은 나를 믿을 것입니다.
Don't take me back.
나를 다시 데려가지 마세요.
Please don't.
그러지 마세요.
If you really don't want to go back...
정말 돌아가고 싶지 않다면...
Are you hungry?
너 배고프 니?
I'll go buy you some food.
내가 가서 음식 좀 사줄게.
Wait here for me.
여기서 기다려주세요.
I just gave you all my money.
방금 내 돈을 다 줬어요.
Hold this lantern.
이 랜턴을 잡아라.
Here.
여기.
I also bought you rice milk.
쌀우유도 사줬어요.
Are you full?
꽉 찼나요?
If I finish this bun,
이 빵을 다 먹으면,
you will take me back to Cuihua Tower?
나를 추이화 타워(Cuihua Tower)로 다시 데려다 주실 건가요?
If you want to go back,
돌아가고 싶다면,
I will take you back.
내가 당신을 다시 데려갈 것이다.
If you don't want to,
원하지 않는다면,
I will pretend I never saw you.
나는 당신을 한 번도 본 적이 없는 척하겠습니다.
What if I can't make up my mind?
마음을 정하지 못하면 어떻게 되나요?
I will wait for you to decide.
나는 당신이 결정하기를 기다릴 것입니다.
I am full.
나는 배불러요.
Take me back to Cuihua Tower.
나를 추이화 타워(Cuihua Tower)로 다시 데려가 주세요.
What happened after that?
그 후에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
I came back and started to entertain clients.
나는 돌아와서 고객을 즐겁게하기 시작했습니다.
I became popular very soon.
나는 곧 인기를 얻었습니다.
Well,
잘,
half a year later,
반년 후,
your father came.
네 아버지가 오셨어.
This is not even enough to pay Siniang for a chat.
이것은 Siniang에게 채팅 비용을 지불하기에 충분하지 않습니다 .
Sir.
선생님.
Why don't you switch to someone else?
다른 사람으로 바꾸는 게 어때요?
I don't want anyone else.
나는 다른 사람을 원하지 않습니다.
How much does it cost
비용은 얼마입니까?
to chat with her?
그 사람이랑 얘기하려고?
20 taels of silver.
은화 20냥.
Wait a minute.
잠깐 기다려요.
Ms. Zhao, don't you remember him?
자오 씨, 그 사람을 기억하지 못하시나요?
He is...
그는...
He is the bailiff who saved me.
그는 나를 구해준 집행관입니다.
He didn't wear an official uniform.
그는 공식 유니폼을 입지 않았습니다.
I didn't recognize him.
나는 그를 알아보지 못했습니다.
Let me spend some time with him.
그 사람과 시간을 좀 보내도록 할게요.
I'll talk with him.
그 사람이랑 얘기 좀 해볼게.
It can be a way to repay his kindness.
그것은 그의 친절에 보답하는 방법이 될 수 있습니다.
I know you love money so much.
당신이 돈을 그토록 사랑하는 걸 알아요.
But if other officials know
하지만 다른 관계자가 알면
you are so ungrateful and send away
넌 너무 배은망덕해서 보내버리네
the savior of my life,
내 인생의 구원자,
none of them will be willing to help you
그들 중 누구도 당신을 도와주려고 하지 않을 거예요
when you need them.
필요할 때.
Sir.
선생님.
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you.
당신을 알아보지 못해 미안해요.
You will forgive me, right?
당신은 나를 용서할 것입니다, 그렇죠?
It's alright.
괜찮아.
Even though I'm a businesswoman,
제가 사업가이긴 하지만,
I'm grateful.
감사해요.
Are you?
당신은?
Of course.
물론.
That's important to us.
그것은 우리에게 중요합니다.
The scholar, Mr. Wang
학자 왕 씨
is a regular here.
여기 단골이에요.
He once said
그는 한때 말했다
there must be women
여자가 있어야 해
of sentiment in a pleasure house.
즐거움의 집에서의 감정.
The tea is already cold.
차는 이미 식었어요.
I'll have someone get you some hot tea.
누군가에게 따뜻한 차를 갖다 드릴께요.
No, thanks.
고맙지 만 사양 할게.
I'm leaving now.
나는 지금 떠난다.
Now?
지금?
Why did you come here?
너는 여기에 왜 왔니?
Just to see you.
그냥 당신을 만나러.
To see me?
나를 만나러?
It costs money to see me.
나를 만나려면 돈이 든다.
Don't spend your money on me anymore.
더 이상 나에게 돈을 쓰지 마세요.
I'm not worth it.
나는 그럴 가치가 없습니다.
I've saved for eight months,
8개월 동안 저축했어요.
getting around six taels of silver.
은화 6냥 정도를 얻었습니다.
To have tea with you,
당신과 함께 차를 마시기 위해,
it costs 20 taels.
가격은 20Taels입니다.
In this case,
이 경우,
I can see you once
한번 만나 볼 수 있어요
every two years.
2년마다.
What's the point?
점은 무엇인가?
It doesn't matter.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
However,
하지만,
the thought
생각
of never seeing you again
다시는 당신을 볼 수 없다는 것
is killing me.
나를 죽이고있다.
Yanzhi Alley.
옌즈 골목.
The back door of Cuihua Tower is on Yanzhi Alley.
Cuihua Tower의 뒷문은 Yanzhi Alley에 있습니다.
Wait for me there three days later
3일 뒤에 거기서 나를 기다려주세요
at six in the evening.
저녁 6시에.
I'll go to see you.
나는 당신을 만나러 갈 것이다.
So you were in a relationship before my father married my mother.
그러니까 당신은 내 아버지가 내 어머니와 결혼하기 전에도 연애 중이셨어요 .
You are from Cuihua Tower,
당신은 추이화 타워(Cuihua Tower) 출신입니다.
so you two cannot be together.
그러니까 너희 둘은 함께 있을 수 없어.
Actually, your father once redeemed me.
사실, 당신의 아버지는 한때 나를 구속했습니다.
To redeem me,
나를 구속하기 위해,
your father did a lot of things
네 아버지는 많은 일을 하셨어
he shouldn't have done.
그는 그러지 말았어야 했어요.
After he really redeemed me,
그가 정말로 나를 구원한 후에,
I realized
나는 깨달았다
my body could never be redeemed
내 몸은 결코 구원받을 수 없어
ever since he brought me back
그 사람이 나를 다시 데려온 이후로
to Cuihua Tower.
추이화 타워(Cuihua Tower)로.
Why?
왜?
I'm 38 this year.
저는 올해 38세입니다.
One in ten prostitutes
매춘부 10명 중 1명
can live
살 수 있다
this long.
이 길다.
Really?
정말?
Most of us could be killed
우리 대부분은 죽을 수도 있다
by being pregnant.
임신해서.
They won't let us give birth once we are pregnant.
우리가 임신하면 출산을 못하게 하지요 .
The abortion method is deadly.
낙태 방법은 치명적입니다.
It involves medicines
의약품이 포함됩니다
like cinnabar, cantharides,
진사, 칸타리데스와 같은
and a little dose of arsenic.
그리고 약간의 비소.
It could kill two lives together.
두 사람의 생명을 함께 죽일 수도 있습니다.
And some survived and gave birth.
그리고 일부는 살아남아 출산했습니다.
But life for them is bitter.
그러나 그들에게 삶은 씁쓸하다.
Their kids are called turtles.
그들의 아이들은 거북이라고 불립니다.
Ms. Lin.
린 씨.
Have you ever
넌 해본 적 있니
been pregnant before?
전에 임신했어?
I've never been pregnant.
나는 임신한 적이 없습니다.
If I can't bear children,
내가 아이를 낳지 못한다면,
how can I marry your father?
어떻게 하면 네 아버지와 결혼할 수 있지?
Fortunately, your father married your mother.
다행히 당신의 아버지는 당신의 어머니와 결혼하셨습니다.
Look.
바라보다.
He's lucky.
그는 운이 좋다.
He has a daughter so much like him.
그에게는 그와 너무나 똑같은 딸이 있습니다.
How did you know the money was from me?
그 돈이 나에게서 온 것이라는 것을 어떻게 알았나요?
Your money is scented.
당신의 돈에는 향기가 있습니다.
You didn't come to return it to me, did you?
나 한테 돌려주러 온 건 아니지 ?
I wanted to ask about my dad and Mr. Xue.
나는 아버지와 Xue 씨에 대해 물어보고 싶었습니다.
Or should I ask about my dad and Lu Zhi?
아니면 아버지와 Lu Zhi에 대해 물어봐야 할까요?
Sui Laosan.
수이 라오산.
Coming.
오는.
Ms. Lin, what can I do for you?
린 씨, 무엇을 도와드릴까요?
Bring the new brocade to...
새 브로케이드를 가져오세요...
To this gentleman.
이 신사에게.
The one with azure color, densely woven with gold and silver thread.
하늘빛을 띠고 금실과 은실로 촘촘하게 짜여진 것입니다.
Got it.
알았어요.
Leave the door open.
문을 열어 두십시오.
I want to get some air.
나는 공기를 좀 마시고 싶다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Bring Sangeng over.
Sangeng을 데려오세요.
I'll tell him everything I know.
나는 그에게 내가 아는 모든 것을 말해줄 것이다.
Gui's.
구이.
You must not get involved.
개입해서는 안 됩니다.
You must not have any connection
아무런 연관도 없어야 합니다
with Mr. Xue.
Xue 씨와 함께.
This must be it.
이것이 틀림없어요.
It's the only new tomb here.
이곳에 있는 유일한 새 무덤이에요.
Ms. Lin.
린 씨.
When you meet my father down there,
저 아래서 아버지를 만나면,
have a good life with him.
그 사람과 잘 지내요.
Don't part ways again.
다시는 헤어지지 마세요.
Gui's.
구이.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
She's suffered too much.
그녀는 너무 많은 고통을 겪었습니다.
I wanted to get a tombstone for her.
나는 그녀를 위해 묘비를 얻고 싶었습니다.
But on the tombstone,
그런데 묘비에는
there's a title in front of the name,
이름 앞에 제목이 있어요.
like mother, sister, or wife.
어머니, 자매, 아내처럼.
But...
하지만...
I don't know what to inscribe for her.
나는 그녀를 위해 무엇을 새겨야할지 모르겠습니다.
My mother suffered as well,
엄마도 고생하셨고
but not as much as she did.
하지만 그녀만큼은 아니었어.
My mother has me and my brother,
엄마는 저와 남동생이 있어요.
but she only has a lonely tomb
하지만 그녀에겐 외로운 무덤밖에 없어
without even a stone.
돌 하나도 없이.
Did the killer leave a note for Ms. Lin as well?
범인은 린 씨에게도 메모를 남겼나요 ?
In his youth his vital force is unstable.
젊었을 때에는 그의 생명력이 불안정하다.
He should guard against lust.
그는 정욕을 경계해야 한다.
It is easy.
쉽습니다.
Even I could understand it.
나조차도 그것을 이해할 수 있었다.
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
What do you think that phrase means?
그 말이 무슨 뜻이라고 생각하시나요?
Youths are prone to impulsiveness.
청소년들은 충동적인 경향이 있습니다.
So be careful of lust for women.
그러므로 여자의 음욕을 조심하라.
No.
아니요.
I'm not right?
내가 옳지 않은가?
Yes,
예,
you are right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
The problem lies elsewhere.
문제는 다른 곳에 있습니다.
(Worship the wrong ghost.)
(잘못된 유령을 숭배하라.)
The victim is Zhao Youren, an Imperial Scholar.
피해자는 황실 학자 조유렌이다.
He originally came from a respected family.
그는 원래 존경받는 가문 출신이었습니다.
But his family collapsed.
그러나 그의 가족은 무너졌습니다.
He liked to raise pigeons.
그는 비둘기 키우는 것을 좋아했습니다.
He had his throat cut.
그는 목이 베였습니다.
Again?
다시?
The message was written in rouge. It reads, "Worship the wrong ghost."
메시지는 루즈로 작성되었습니다. "잘못된 귀신을 숭배하라"라고 쓰여 있습니다.
You worshiped
당신은 숭배했습니다
the wrong ghost.
잘못된 유령.
I think this killer is using the body to send us messages.
내 생각엔 이 살인자가 우리에게 메시지를 보내기 위해 몸을 사용하고 있는 것 같아요 .
The message left for Lin Siniang is too blunt.
Lin Siniang에게 남긴 메시지는 너무 직설적입니다.
But the previous ones
하지만 이전 것들은
(He should guard against lust.) carry a hidden meaning.
(그는 정욕을 경계해야 한다.) 숨겨진 의미를 가지고 있다.
And this victim has the same cause
그리고 이 피해자도 같은 원인을 가지고 있어요
and state of death as Lin Siniang.
Lin Siniang의 죽음 상태.
He was deliberately dressed up as a woman.
그는 일부러 여자로 변장했다 .
And the message. "Worship the wrong ghost."
그리고 메시지. "잘못된 유령을 숭배하라."
You worshiped the wrong ghost.
당신은 잘못된 유령을 숭배했습니다.
- You mean... - The killer wants to tell us
- 그 말은... - 범인이 우리에게 말하고 싶어하는 것
that he didn't kill Lin Siniang.
그가 Lin Siniang을 죽이지 않았다는 것입니다.
(1589 AD) (Lu Yuanbao's condition was not stable.)
(서기 1589년) (여원보의 상태는 안정되지 않았습니다.)
(It never got better.)
(좀처럼 나아지지 않았습니다.)
(He began to have nightmares,)
(그는 악몽을 꾸기 시작했다)
(dreaming about the deceased.)
(고인에 대한 꿈을 꾸었습니다.)
Guards!
근위 연대!
Lu Zhong.
루 종.
I dreamt of Tao Laowu.
나는 Tao Laowu를 꿈꿨습니다.
(I remember him.)
(나는 그를 기억한다.)
Go kill him.
가서 그를 죽여라.
Kill him.
그를 죽여.
(He was killed 13 years ago.)
(그는 13년 전에 살해당했습니다.)
It's good.
좋다.
Well,
잘,
was he really killed?
그 사람 정말 죽었나요?
Go back to sleep.
돌아가 잠이나 자.
(You stay here.)
(너는 여기 있어라.)
(Watch him. I'm leaving.)
(그 사람 조심해. 난 떠날 거야.)
Tian Shun Xiang.
티안슌샹.
Accounts settled.
계정이 정산되었습니다.
Mr. Li, thank you.
리 선생님, 감사합니다.
Not at all, Master Lu.
전혀 그렇지 않아요, 루 선생님.
Fuxing Shop.
푸싱샵.
Master Lu, are you done?
루 선생님, 끝났어요?
Almost.
거의.
When you're done, go and visit Mr. Lu.
다 끝나면 루 씨를 만나러 가세요.
In the back garden.
뒷 정원에서.
Isn't he in the study?
그 사람 연구실에 있지 않아?
Mr. Lu is in good spirits today and wants to have a drink.
루 씨는 오늘 기분이 좋아서 술을 마시고 싶어합니다.
mr. Sun.
씨. 해.
You've worked hard these days.
요즘 열심히 일하셨어요.
I'm doing my job.
나는 내 일을 하고 있다.
Mr. Lu, this is the account book from last month.
루씨, 이건 지난달의 장부예요 .
No rush.
서두르지 마.
Sit, and have a drink with me.
앉아서 나랑 한잔 하자.
Mr. Lu, Dr. Cheng does not permit you to drink alcohol.
루 선생님, 쳉 박사님은 술을 마시는 것을 허락하지 않습니다.
The doctor only wishes everyone to take medicine.
의사는 모든 사람이 약을 복용하기를 원합니다.
Just ignore him.
그냥 무시하세요.
Bottoms up.
원샷이야.
This is the old grain wine,
이것이 바로 오래된 곡주,
just shipped over via the Yangtze River.
방금 양쯔강을 통해 배송되었습니다.
How's the taste?
맛은 어때요?
Your wine is naturally good.
당신의 와인은 자연적으로 좋습니다.
Sweet boy.
사랑스러운 소년.
Lu Zhi.
루지.
How much can you drink?
얼마나 마실 수 있나요?
I can't drink much.
나는 술을 많이 못 마신다.
Just drink as much as you like.
원하는 만큼만 마셔보세요.
I will test your drinking capacity.
당신의 음주능력을 테스트해보겠습니다.
If you say so,
그렇게 말하면,
I will
그럴게요
get drunk here.
여기서 취하세요.
Drinking like this is boring.
이렇게 마시는 건 지루해요.
We need to play a drinking game.
우리는 술게임을 해야 한다.
Let me guess the account you just settled today.
오늘 방금 정산한 계좌를 추측해 보겠습니다 .
Can you do it?
당신은 그것을 할 수 있습니다?
Within five taels of difference,
다섯 닢의 차이 안에서,
I win.
내가 이겼다.
And you will drink.
그리고 당신은 마실 것입니다.
If I guess wrong, I'll drink.
내 생각이 틀리면 마실게요.
mr. Sun.
씨. 해.
Is this your excuse to drink more?
이게 술을 더 마시려는 핑계인가요?
Do you dare?
감히?
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
You're as outright as me.
당신도 나만큼 솔직해요.
Someone, bring a larger bowl.
누가 좀 더 큰 그릇을 가져오세요.
Let's start.
시작하자.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Hey Shop.
안녕하세요 쇼핑입니다.
Two thousand...
우리...
2,950 taels in total.
총 2,950태엘.
How is it?
어때요?
Guessed right.
추측이 맞았습니다.
Drink up.
마셔 라.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Again.
다시.
Long Chang Sheng.
롱 창 셩.
5,292 taels.
5,292Tael.
You guessed right.
당신의 추측이 맞았습니다.
I'm lucky.
나는 운이 좋다.
Drink.
마시다.
Again.
다시.
Well...
잘...
Wait a moment.
잠시만 기다려주세요.
I will choose one shop.
한 가게를 선택하겠습니다.
And you make a guess.
그리고 당신은 추측을 합니다.
Alright, as you say.
알았어, 네 말대로야.
This is too easy for you.
이것은 당신에게 너무 쉽습니다.
No.
아니요.
This one...
이 하나...
This...
이것...
Lu Zhi.
루지.
I can tell
나는 말할 수있다
you're playing for time.
당신은 시간을두고 놀고 있습니다.
How did you know that?
그걸 어떻게 알았 니?
Lion Restaurant.
라이온 레스토랑.
Lion Restaurant?
라이온 레스토랑?
You got me.
당신은 나를 잡았습니다.
744 taels.
744타엘.
You guessed it right.
당신의 추측이 맞았습니다.
Drink.
마시다.
Okay.
좋아요.
You keep drinking.
당신은 계속 술을 마시고 있습니다.
It's too boring.
너무 지루해요.
I'll join you for a drink.
저도 같이 한잔하겠습니다.
How on earth did you guess it?
도대체 어떻게 추측한 걸까요?
I can guess.
내가 유추 할 수있다.
You can guess.
너는 추측 할 수있다.
Lu Zhi.
루지.
Are you drunk?
취했나요?
mr. Sun.
씨. 해.
Did you
당신은
settle the accounts with the bookkeepers in advance?
장부 담당자와 미리 정산을 합니까 ?
No.
아니요.
You haven't been out for over a month.
당신은 한 달 넘게 밖에 나가지 않았습니다.
And those bookkeepers have never come.
그리고 그 회계원들은 한 번도 오지 않았습니다.
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
Lu Zhi.
루지.
Remember one thing.
한 가지를 기억하십시오.
There is nothing, big or small,
크고 작은 일이 없고,
in my house that I don't know.
내가 모르는 내 집에서.
Mr. Lu, I got it.
루 씨, 알겠습니다.
After they settled accounts
그들이 결산을 한 후
with me,
나랑,
they went
그들은 떠났다
to tell you one by one.
하나하나 말하려고.
You put these accounts in your sleeve.
당신은 이러한 계정을 소매에 넣습니다.
I saw it just now. When you were walking,
지금 막 봤어요. 걷고 있었을 때,
you turned your head and looked inside.
너는 고개를 돌려 안을 들여다보았다.
I saw it.
나는 그것을 보았다.
You're cheating.
당신은 바람을 피우고 있습니다.
You have to drink.
당신은 마셔야합니다.
Lu Zhi.
루지.
You are really drunk.
당신 정말 취했어요.
I'm not drunk.
나는 취하지 않았습니다.
I haven't finished my drink yet.
아직 술을 다 마시지 않았어요.
But why did you make a fool of me?
그런데 왜 나를 바보로 만들었나요?
Are you trying to get me drunk?
나를 취하게 하려는 거야?
No.
아니요.
Even if you didn't do this,
이 일을 안 했어도,
I would still drink a lot.
나는 아직도 술을 많이 마실 것이다.
I understand.
이해합니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
Mr. Lu, you are trying to seem mysterious
루씨, 당신은 신비롭게 보이려고 노력하고 있어요
and well-informed.
그리고 잘 알고 있습니다.
You know everything.
넌 다 아는군.
You are trying to warn me.
당신은 나에게 경고하려고합니다.
So, you don't trust me.
그래서 당신은 나를 믿지 않습니다.
You are trying to scare me.
당신은 나에게 겁을 주려고합니다.
So I dare not mess around.
그래서 나는 감히 장난을 치지 않습니다.
Don't you know me?
당신은 나를 모르나요?
You don't have to do this.
이렇게 할 필요는 없습니다.
Well,
잘,
I have always respected you as my father.
나는 항상 당신을 아버지로서 존경해 왔습니다.
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
mr. Sun.
씨. 해.
Without you,
당신 없이는
I, a beggar,
나, 거지,
would have died on the streets long ago.
오래 전에 거리에서 죽었을 겁니다.
Although you don't have a son.
비록 당신에게는 아들이 없지만.
I can be your son.
나는 당신의 아들이 될 수 있습니다.
I will certainly respect you more than anyone.
나는 누구보다 당신을 확실히 존경할 것입니다.
I will take care of you during your later life.
나는 당신의 노후 생활 동안 당신을 돌볼 것입니다 .
I will mourn for you.
나는 당신을 위해 슬퍼할 것입니다.
mr. Sun.
씨. 해.
I have always wanted to call you father.
나는 항상 당신을 아버지라고 부르고 싶었습니다.
Lu Zhi.
루지.
They all call you Master Lu.
그들은 모두 당신을 Master Lu라고 부릅니다.
Why?
왜?
They keep calling me that.
계속 그렇게 불러요.
They have seen how well you treat me.
그들은 당신이 나를 얼마나 잘 대하는지 보았습니다.
I tried to stop them.
나는 그들을 막으려고 노력했습니다.
I told them to stop calling me that,
그런 식으로 전화하지 말라고 했어요.
but they didn't listen to me...
하지만 그들은 내 말을 듣지 않았습니다 ...
You lowly beast.
이 보잘것없는 짐승아.
Do you want a father?
아버지를 원하시나요?
I'll give you one.
내가 하나 줄게.
You know this lowly servant on his knees.
당신은 무릎을 꿇은 이 비천한 종을 아십니다 .
My attendant, Lu Zhi.
내 수행자 Lu Zhi입니다.
Somehow,
어떻게든,
he was possessed,
그는 홀린 상태였고,
telling everyone
모두에게 말하다
that I wanted to take him as my adopted son.
나는 그를 나의 양자로 삼고 싶었다 .
He even let everyone call him Master Lu.
그는 심지어 모든 사람이 그를 Master Lu라고 부르도록 했습니다.
What are you?
너 뭐야?
A lowly servant.
낮은 하인.
How dare you.
감히.
I just kept you as a dog,
난 그냥 당신을 개처럼 키웠어요
but you took yourself for a man.
하지만 당신은 자신을 남자로 여겼어요.
He said he would take care of me in my old age.
그는 노년에도 나를 돌봐주겠다고 말했습니다 .
I know your trick.
나는 당신의 속임수를 알고 있습니다.
You think that since I have no children,
당신은 내가 아이가 없기 때문에 그렇게 생각합니다.
all my property will belong to you.
내 재산은 모두 당신의 것이 될 것입니다.
You want a father, right?
당신은 아버지를 원해요, 그렇죠?
All the men of the Lu family are here.
루 가문의 남자들이 모두 여기에 있습니다.
Later, kowtow
나중에, kowtow
and ask each man
그리고 각자에게 물어봐
who wants to be your father.
네 아버지가 되고 싶은 사람.
If his surname is Zhang,
성(姓)이 장(張)이면
your name will be Zhang Zhi.
당신의 이름은 Zhang Zhi가 될 것입니다.
If his surname is Li,
그의 성이 리(Li)라면,
your name will be Li Zhi.
당신의 이름은 Li Zhi가 될 것입니다.
Do it now.
지금 그것을 할.
Help him.
그를 도와 라.
Speak.
말하다.
Slap him.
그를 때리세요.
Go on.
계속해.
Hit him until he speaks.
그가 말할 때까지 때리세요.
mr. Sun.
씨. 해.
I'll speak for him.
제가 그를 대신해 말씀드리겠습니다.
What a surprise.
놀랐는 걸.
I can't believe you'll help him with it.
당신이 그 사람을 도와줄 거라 믿을 수가 없어요.
Chen Wang, you are quite righteous.
Chen Wang, 당신은 매우 의롭습니다.
But I admire righteous people.
그러나 나는 의로운 사람들을 존경합니다.
Then you two find a father together.
그러면 두 사람은 함께 아버지를 찾습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Well...
잘...
Kowtow.
돈수.
Okay.
좋아요.
Miao, are you willing...
미아오, 당신도 할 수 있나요...
Louder.
더 크게.
Miao, are you willing to be a father
먀오족, 아버지가 될 의향이 있나요?
to me and Lu Zhi?
나와 Lu Zhi에게?
Miao, did you hear?
미아오, 들었어?
Yes, I did.
그래, 내가 했어.
So what do you say?
그래서 당신은 무엇을 말합니까?
I...
나...
I am unwilling.
나는 원하지 않는다.
Miao, you lost your chance.
미아오, 당신은 기회를 잃었어요.
Step aside.
비켜서 다.
Are you willing to be our father?
우리 아버지가 되어주실 의향이 있으신가요?
No.
아니요.
Chen Wang.
첸 왕.
I'll do it myself.
내가 직접 할게.
Are you willing to be my father?
기꺼이 내 아버지가 되어 주시겠습니까?
No.
아니요.
(In the end, Lu Zhi didn't get a father.)
(결국 Lu Zhi는 아버지를 얻지 못했습니다.)
(Later, )
(나중에, )
(Lu Yuanbao sent him to a rural area)
(루위안바오는 그를 시골로 보냈다)
(to do farm work.)
(농사일을 하려고.)
Lu Zhi.
루지.
Where are the others?
다른 사람들은 어디에 있나요?
(You asked them to wait outside.)
(당신은 그들에게 밖에서 기다려달라고 요청했습니다.)
I was absorbed in writing and forgot.
나는 글쓰기에 열중해서 잊어버렸다.
(I heard you.)
(네 말 들었어.)
(You didn't call them.)
(당신은 그들에게 전화하지 않았습니다.)
Lu Zhong.
루 종.
According to the rules,
규칙에 따르면,
we should...
우리는 ...
(Kill him.)
(그를 죽여.)
(I'll do it.)
(나는 그것을 할 거 야.)
I've thought about it these days.
요즘 그런 생각을 했어요.
Well,
잘,
I overreacted.
나는 과잉 반응했다.
After that day,
그날 이후,
this kid must have hated me.
이 아이는 나를 싫어했나 보다.
I can't use him anymore.
더 이상 그를 사용할 수 없습니다.
It's quite a pity.
정말 안타깝습니다.
(Keeping him is dangerous.)
(그를 지키는 것은 위험하다.)
(I'm afraid...)
(두려워요...)
You're afraid of him?
그 사람이 무서워요?
He's just a servant.
그는 단지 하인일 뿐입니다.
He can't be compared to the others.
그는 다른 사람들과 비교할 수 없습니다.
Those were ruthless bandits.
그들은 무자비한 도적이었습니다.
He's just an attendant.
그는 단지 수행자일 뿐입니다.
I just pampered him too much.
나는 단지 그를 너무 애지중지했습니다.
So he dared to be presumptuous in front of me.
그래서 그는 감히 내 앞에서 뻔뻔하게 행동했습니다 .
I have to make him afraid.
나는 그를 두려워하게 만들어야 한다.
When I call him,
내가 그에게 전화를 하면,
he will shiver.
그는 떨 것이다.
When I glare,
내가 눈부실 때,
he will wet his pants.
그는 바지를 적실 것이다.
It's fun.
재미있다.
Call him back in a few days.
며칠 후에 다시 전화하세요.
He can't be my attendant.
그 사람은 내 수행원이 될 수 없어요.
Let him do some kind of rough work.
그에게 힘든 일을 시키십시오.
If he makes any movements,
그 사람이 조금이라도 움직이면,
don't hesitate.
주저하지 마십시오.
Mr. Zhong.
종 씨.
(Let's find a private place.)
(사적인 장소를 찾아보자.)
Mr. Zhong, have you gone fishing?
종 씨, 낚시하러 가셨나요?
There's fat fish in the river.
강에는 살찐 물고기가 있어요.
Mr. Lu asked me to kill you.
루 씨가 나에게 당신을 죽여달라고 부탁했습니다.
(At that time, I told Lu Zhi)
(그때 나는 Lu Zhi에게 말했다)
(that Mr. Lu asked me to kill him.)
(루 씨가 나에게 자신을 죽여달라고 부탁했다는 것입니다.)
(No Rank in Penalty)
(벌점 순위 없음)
???In the middle of the bone, and beside the blade???
???뼈 중앙, 칼날 옆???
???There's something sweet and sticky???
???뭔가 달콤하고 끈적한 느낌???
???Biting through the old time???
???옛날을 깨물고???
???Some cry, and some sleep???
???누구는 울고 누구는 자고???
???Abundant offerings are served for sacrifice???
???제사를 위해 풍성한 제물을 드리는가???
???There are barren mounds, with flies flying around???
??? 파리가 날아다니는 황량한 언덕이 있나요 ???
???Remote ancient road and prosperous city???
???외딴 고대 도로 와 번영하는 도시???
???Wild fires never cease, withering and flourishing???
???야생의 불은 결코 그치지 않고 시들고 번성합니다???
???A few columns of smoke are curling up???
???몇개의 연기기둥이 뭉게뭉게 피어오르고 있나요???
???You make a wish???
???소원을 빌고 계시나요???
???Empty promises and miserable stories???
???공허한 약속과 비참한 이야기???
???Disappear without trace???
???흔적없이 사라져???
???Abundant offerings are served for sacrifice???
???제사를 위해 풍성한 제물을 드리는가???
???There are barren mounds, with flies flying around???
??? 파리가 날아다니는 황량한 언덕이 있나요 ???
???Remote ancient road and prosperous city???
???외딴 고대 도로 와 번영하는 도시???
???Wild fires never cease, withering and flourishing???
???야생의 불은 결코 그치지 않고 시들고 번성합니다???